Guide to the United Hatters, Cap, and Millinery Workers International Union Records TAM.054
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
United Hatters, Cap, and Millinery Workers International Union Records
1827-1978
1896-1934
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
United Hatters, Cap, and Millinery Workers International Union
Coleman, Gerald R.
TAM.054
42 Linear Feet in 72 boxes and 1 folder in a shared oversize box.
The United Hatters Cap and Millinery Workers International Union (UHCMW) was formed in 1934 by the amalgamation of United Hatters of North America (UHNA) and the Cloth Hat, Cap and Millinery Workers International Union (CHCMW). About two thirds of the collection consists of the separate records of these two unions prior to their merger, and of records of joint bodies established in the decade prior to the merger. The materials pertaining to the Danbury Hatters' Case comprise about one fifth of the collection. The remainder consists of records of earlier unionizing efforts among hatters, and of the UHCMW in the decades following the merger, and a set of of primary source research materials and notes compiled by Charles H. Green for his book The Headgear Workers. The collection contains minutes, scrapbooks (financial and membership records), clippings, ephemera, photographs, histories and biographies, and legal documents.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by the United Hatters, Cap and Millinery Workers International Union via the union's executive secretary Gerald R. Coleman, 1973. The accession numbers associated with this gift are 1954.001, 1954.003, and NPA 2000.076.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Historical/Biographical Note
The United Hatters Cap and Millinery Workers International Union (UHCMW) was formed in 1934 by the amalgamation of United Hatters of North America (UHNA) and the Cloth Hat, Cap and Millinery Workers International Union (CHCMW). The United Hatters of North America (UHNA) was established in New York in 1896 as the result of the merger of two Knights of Labor-affiliated unions in the men's hat industry, the the Hat Makers and the Hat Finishers. The Cloth Hat, Cap and Millinery Workers International Union (CHCMW) was established in New York in 1901, as the United Cloth Hat and Cap Makers of North America (superceding the the Cloth Hat and Cap Operators Union), and took its final name (adding Millinery Workers) in 1918. In 1983 the UHCMW joined the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union, which in turn merged in 1995 with the Internional Ladies Garment Workers Union to form UNITE (Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees).
Sources:
For additional information, see Labor Unions (Westport, CT: Greenwood Press, 1977), pp. 139-144, for historical sketches of the various hatters unions.
Scope and Content Note
The records of the early hatters unions concentrate on the International Trade Association of Hat Finishers of America, and include the union's convention minutes, officers' reports (which include financial and membership records), and scattered presidential reports on major problems confronting union. (See Series IX: Scrapbooks for the Hat Finishers of North America Executive Board minutes.) There are also minute books for three locals: Brooklyn (1868-1893), Boston (1868-1882), and Newark (1853 1870), as well as list of apprentices in Bethel, Conn. (1860-1892). Other affiliated groups represented by various documents here are: Silk Hat and Fur Finishers' Union, Hat Makers National Union, Wool Hat Finishers Convention proceedings, and the Convention of Hatters to fight convict labor proceedings.
The extensive records of the United Hatters of North America include: convention proceedings, several constitutions of UHNA and locals, financial records (including some strike benefit records), records of union labels issued to employers, records taken from individual applications, and miscellaneous files on such issues as communist activities within the union and relations between United Hatters and Cloth Hatters.
The Cloth Hat, Cap and Millinery Workers International Union national office records include National Executive Board minutes, general Executive Board minutes, and correspondence on jurisdiction. Other files relate the union's stormy relationship with the International Workers of the World, and contain scrapbooks and pamphlets on factional, jurisdictional and racketeering issues. There is also a typescript of a biography of Max Zuckerman. Some of the correspondence here and in the United Hatters section also relates to jurisdictional disputes between the United Hatters and the Cloth flatters, and the latter and the American Federation of Labor. The disputes between the United Hatters and the Cloth Hatters were resolved through amalgamation following a series of conventions in 1933-1934, the records of which comprise one section of this collection. Two additional boxes contain the financial records of the Joint Union Label Board, a cooperative endeavor of the United Hatters and Cloth Hatters.
The large body of material on the Danbury Hatters' Case (Loewe v. Lawlor), in which the Supreme Court first declared secondary boycotts illegal, includes: court transcripts, records of negotiations between the unions and the hat manufacturers, local newspaper clippings, government and employer comment, and records of strike benefits, local unions, and the property holdings of the hatters attached by the court. There are also court transcripts of related cases involving hatters. After 1934 the United Hat, Cap, and Millinery Workers International Union (UHCMW) was the only hatters union in the U.S. Documents found here on the UHCMW include records of union labels issues, and arbitratration proceedings, as well as some records and proceedings relating to the millinery industry codes of the National Recovery Administration under the New Deal. There are also several pamphlets and reports, including "Business Mortality of the Millinery Industry" (1942) by Edward Wagenfeld.
This collection also includes material assembled by Charles H. Green for his 1944 authorized history of hatters' unionism, The Headgear Workers. Of particular interest is material not included in his study that covers technological developments in the industry, its economic history, and trade associations. Addresses and brief histories of the union by union officials, Max Zaritsky and others, are included. There are also documents relating to the conduct of locals, apprenticeship indentures, mortuary benefits, and a handwritten constitution, dated 1827, of a Cincinnati hatters local.
Approximately fifty photographs and seventeen scrapbooks are included in the collection. The first scrapbook contains International Association of Hat Finishers of North America minutes (1836-1893). The rest contain United Hatters of North America materials, including twelve membership books for the various trades, two petty cash registers, a strike benefits book, and a World War I clippings scrapbook.
Related Archival Materials
United Hatters, Cap, and Millinery Workers International Union, Millinery Workers Joint Board Records (WAG 041)
United Hatters, Cap, and Millinery Workers International Union Printed Ephemera Collection (PE 006)
Arrangement
Folders are generally arranged chronologically. Series XI has not been arranged by an archivist. The collection is arranged into eleven series:
Series I: Hatters Unions,1853-1896
Series II: United Hatters of North America, 1886-1934
Series III: Cloth Hat, Cap and Millinery Workers International, 1901-1934
Series IV: Jurisdictional Disputes and Amalgamation, 1933-1934
Series V: Joint Union Labor Board, 1920-1932
Series VI: Danbury Hatters Case, 1906-1922
Series VII: United Hattes, Cap and Millinery Workers International, 1934-1954
Series VIII: Charles H. Green Headger Workers Research Collection, 1827-1944
Series IX: Scrapbooks, 1886-1932
Series X: Photographs, 1929-1953
Series XI: Addendum (Unprocessed), 1876-1978
Folders are generally arranged alphabetically.
The records are arranged in ten series:
V.
I. Hatters Unions (1853-1896)
II. United Hatters of North America (1886-1934)
III. Cloth Hat, Cap and Millinery Workers International (1901-1934)
IV. Jurisdictional Disputes and Amalgamation (1933-1934)
V. Joint Union Labor Board (1920-1932)
VI. Danbury Hatters Case (1906-1922)
VII. United Hattes, Cap and Millinery Workers International (1934-1954)
VIII. Charles H. Green Headger Workers Research Collection (1827-1944)
IX. Scrapbooks.
X. Addendum.
Oral histories (literary works); Biographies.; Pamphlets.; Scrapbooks.; Loewe v. Lawlor.; Danbury Hatters Case.; Millinery workers |z United States.; Labor unions -- United States.; Hat trade |z United States.; Clippings (information artifacts); Labor -- United States.; Black-and-white photographs.; Artifacts (object genre); Speeches.; Green, Charles H.; Cloth Hat, Cap, and Millinery Workers' International Union; Industrial Workers of the World; Zuckerman, Max; Zaritsky, Max, 1885-1959; United States. National Recovery Administration; United Hatters of North America; Gompers, Samuel, 1850-1924.; Joint Union Label Board; International Association of Hat Finishers of America; United Hatters, Cap, and Millinery Workers International Union; Coleman, Gerald R.
- Series I: Hatters Unions, 1853-1896
  - Minutes of Convention Proceedings, 1854-1886 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Directory of Union, Fur Hat Manufacturers, 1891 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Minutes, Brooklyn Local Meetings, 1868-1883 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook of Brooklyn Labor News Clippings, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Typescript of Legal Decision on Presidential Succession of D.J. Hagerty and John Bouton, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Label of Hat Makers, May 28, 1895 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Philip Thomas' Indenture, 1907-1912 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - List of Registered Apprentices-Bethel, CT, 1860-1892 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Minute Book, Newark Hat Finishers, 1853-1870 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Minute Book, Boston Fur Hat Finishers, 1868-1893 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Constitution-Orange, NJ Local, 1854 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Constitution-Norwalk, CT Local, 1873 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Records of Silk Hat Finishers Association, undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Card of Wool Hat Finishers, Jul 1, 1892 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Hat Making a reprinted article from Brooklyn Daily Standard, Aug 27, 1894 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Mementos, 1864,1892 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Series II: United Hatters of North America, 1886-1934
  - Convention Proceedings, typescript, verbatim, 1907 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Convention Proceedings, typescript, verbatim, 1911 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - United Hatters Of North America: Convention Proceedings, typescript, verbatim, 1915 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - United Hatters Of North America: Convention Proceedings, typescript, verbatim (vol. 1), 1919 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - United Hatters Of North America: Convention Proceedings, typescript, verbatim (vol. 2), 1919 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - United Hatters Of North America: Convention Proceedings, typescript, verbatim (vol. 1), 1923 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - United Hatters Of North America: Convention Proceedings, typescript, verbatim (vol. 2), 1923 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - United Hatters Of North America: Convention Proceedings, typescript, verbatim (vol. 1), 1927 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - United Hatters Of North America: Convention Proceedings, typescript, verbatim (vol. 2), 1927 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Directory of the Union Fur Hat Manufacturers of the United States, 1898 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Constitution and By-Laws:Local District 1, United Hatters Of North America-Bethel, CT, 1903 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Constitution and By-Laws:United Hatters Of North America, 1907-1927 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Constitution and By-Laws: Local 3, United Hatters Of North America-New York, NY, May 5, 1919 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Constitution and By-Laws:Union #11, United Hatters Of North America-Danbury, CT, Feb 3, 1932 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - United Hatters Of North America: Pamphlet, undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Record of Reciepts, 1896-1918 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Reciepts of Traveling Cards, 1899-1911 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Secretary's Expense Book 1, 1902-1907 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Secretary's Expense Book 2, 1907-1911 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Record of Special Assessments, 1905-1917 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Record of Dues Paid by Districts-at-Large, 1914-1918 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Secretary's Expense Book 3, 1911-1916 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Traveling Card Dues Records, 1911-1918 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Traveling Card Dues, 1917-1918 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Secretary's Expense Book 4, 1917-1918 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Record of Traveling Cards, 1917-1919 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Ledger-Orange, NJ, 1911 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Application Fees and Dues Records from Straw Hatters, 1916-1918 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Traveling Cards, 1920-1929 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Traveling Cards, 1929-1936 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Strike Benefits Paid, 1909 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Strike Benefits Paid, 1913-1921 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Ledger: Cash Received on Percentage from Locals, 1896-1918 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Ledger: Regular Expense Account, 1911-1918 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Defense Fund Account, Jan 1, 1911-Jun 30, 1918 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Strike Benefits-Beacon, NY, Oct 7, 1921-Dec 31, 1921 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Members Who Owe Dues to International, 1932-1936 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Financial Statement to Secretary Gordon, Local 10-Danbury, CT, 1931-1933 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Reciepts of Local 42, for Money Refunded, 1931-1933 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Signed Statements of Hat Companies, undated (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Wills of Members, undated (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous Checks, 1909-1930 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Bank Books of Martin Lawlor, Joint Union Label Board Relief Fund, 1904-1918 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Information Taken From Applications to Union From Various Locals, 1919-1932 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Records Taken From Individual Applications: Finishers A-G, 1919-1932 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Records Taken From Individual Applications: Finishers H-O, 1919-1932 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Records Taken From Individual Applications: Finishers P-Z, 1919-1932 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Records Taken From Individual Applications: Trimmers and Operators A-K, 1919-1932 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Records Taken From Individual Applications: Trimmers and Operators L-Z, 1919-1932 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Records Taken From Individual Applications: Makers A-L, 1919-1932 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Records Taken From Individual Applications: Makers M-Z, 1919-1932 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Communist Activities in United Hatters, undated (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Adjourned Meeting of the Fur Felt Hat Manufacturing Association of Danbury, Bethel and the National Executive Advisory Board, Dec 7, 1909-Dec 16, 1909 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Record of Union Labels Distributed by the Union, 1902-1911 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous Material on Union Labels, 1896-1921 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Labor Clippings on Newark, NJ, 1917-1935 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Applications of Stetson Makers and Finishers, Schobel Makers and Finishers, and LaSalle Finishers (copied from Record Books), undated (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Court of Common Pleas, Fairfield County-Writ, Summons and Complaint: A. Berg and Company v. United Hatters, Sep 1925 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Superior Court, Fairfield County-Complaint, Temporary Injunction, Order to Show Cause: R and W Hat Company v. Jeremiah Scully et al, Apr 1922 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Supreme Court, State of New York: Cortland Hat Company v. Michael Green, United Hatters, Jul 22, 1921 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Supreme Court of Errors, 3rd Judicial District, Fairfield County-Suit of Injunction: R and W Hat Company v. Jeremiah Scully et a., Apr 1922 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Superior Court, Fairfield County-Motion to Dissolve Temporary Injunction: R and W Hat Company v. Jeremiah Scully, Aug 1, 1919 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Supreme Court of Errors, 3rd Judicial District-Defendants Appeal: Goralnik v. The Delhery Hat Company, Jan 1923 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Agreement of Affiliation: Local 12 and United Hatters, Oct 16, 1916 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Supreme Court, New York County-Order to Show Cause: Jacob Elishewitz v. Michael Green et al, Sep 23, 1921 (Box 18, Folder 8)
- Series III: Cloth Hat, Cap, and Millinery Workers International, 1901-1934
  - National Executive Board Minutes, 1904-1907 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - National Executive Board Minutes, 1907-1911 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - National Executive Board Minutes, 1911-1913 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - National Executive Board Minutes, 1913-1917 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - General Executive Board Minutes, 1901-1904 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - General Executive Board Minutes, 1917-1920 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - General Executive Board Minutes, 1920-1923 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Convention Proceedings, typescript, 1907 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - United Hatters-Executive Board Minutes, May 10, 1923-Nov 3, 1923 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - United Hatters-Executive Board Minutes, Feb 2, 1924-Jan 30, 1925 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - United Hatters-Executive Board Minutes, Apr 27, 1925-Aug 17, 1925 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - United Hatters-Executive Board Minutes, Oct 22, 1925-Feb 20, 1926 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - United Hatters-Executive Board Minutes, May 20, 1926-Feb 27, 1927 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - United Hatters-Executive Board Minutes, Apr 19, 1927-Mar 3, 1928 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - United Hatters-Executive Board Minutes, Mar 3, 1928-Mar 10, 1928 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - United Hatters-Executive Board Minutes, Mar 10, 1928-Mar 23, 1928 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - United Hatters-Executive Board Minutes, May 25, 1928-Jan 30, 1929 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence on Jurisdiction, 1903-1916 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence on Jurisdiction, 1916-1918 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence on Jurisdiction, 1917-1921 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence on Jurisdiction, 1922-1926 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence on Jurisdiction, 1931-1933 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Research Memorandum (from Braunthals files) on Racketeering, undated (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Clippings on Jurisdictional Problems and Racketeering (in Yiddish), 1931-1933 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Convention Documents (in Yiddish), 1901 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence on Jurisdiction (AFL), 1919-1926 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence on Jurisdiction (AFL), 1930-1934 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - I.W.W. Dues Books, 1896-1907 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Minutes of Meetings of the Joint Education Committee, 1917 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Constitution of the Union, 1923 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Supreme Court of the State of New York, Appellate Division-2nd Department:People of the State of New York v. Raul Smith and Zolot, 1916 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Supreme Court of the State of New York, Appellate Division-1st Department: Hersh Kovitz v. Good Value Hat Company, 1933 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence from J.B. Salsberg to the General Executive Board (5 pieces), undated (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Scrapbook (in Yiddish and English), 1904-1916 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Stories from Daily Worker (on factional fights), 1920's (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Whither are we Going? (speech on resignation of Zaritsky), undated (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Biography of Max Zuckerman, typescript, undated (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - The Millinery Workers Turn the Tide Max Zuckerman (pamphlet), 1932 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Articles on Agreement with Cap Manufacturers, 1902-1932 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Credentials of Delegates to Convention, 1901 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - The Deceit of the I.W.W. (pamphlet), 1906 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Constitution, 1901 (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - International Socialist and Labor Greetings, 1894-1923 (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - The Facts of the Case (pamphlets about jurisdictional fight), undated (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Millinery and Ladies' Straw Hat Workers Union: 24th Anniversary Dinner Souvenir, Mar 19, 1916 (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - Millinery Workers Union: 20th Anniversary Concert and Banquet Program, May 29, 1930 (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - Charter of Kansas City Local, Oct 24, 1933 (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - Untranslated Yiddish Handwritten Document, undated (Box 26, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence: United Cloth Hatters and Cap Makers and AFL, 1917-1919 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: United Cloth Hatters and Cap Makers and AFL, 1927-1929 (Box 27, Folder 2)
- Series IV: Jurisdictional Disputes and Amalgamation, 1933-1934
  - Proceedings: Special Amalgamation Convention of the United Hatters (vol. 1), Oct 1933 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Proceedings: Special Amalgamation Convention of the United Hatters (vol. 2), Oct 1933 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Proceedings: Special Amalgamation Convention of the United Hatters (vol. 3), Oct 1933 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Proceedings: Adjourned Session of the Special Convention of the Men's Hat Department of the United Hatters (vol. 1), Jan 1934 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Proceedings: Adjourned Session of the Special Convention of the Men's Hat Department of the United Hatters (vol. 2), Jan 1934 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Bills of Local 42, Cloth Hatters-Signed on Joining United Hatters, undated (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - List if Indebtedness of Local 42, undated (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Agreements: United Hatters and Cloth Hatters, undated (Box 29, Folder 3)
- Series V: Joint Union Label Board, 1920-1932
  - Record of Labels Distributed to Employers, 1920-1927 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Record of Labels Distributed to Employers, 1920-1932 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Expense Account of Joint Union Label Board, 1925-1929 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Expense Account of Joint Union Label Board, 1927, 1929 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Joint Union Label Board: Checkbook, 1925-1928 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Joint Union Label Board: Checkbook, 1928-1929 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Joint Union Label Board: Bank Book, 1925-1929 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Joint Union Label Board: Cancelled Checks, undated (Box 31, Folder 4)
- Series VI: Danbury Hatters' Case, 1905-1922
  - Circuit Court of the United States, District of CT: Dietrich E. Loewe v. Martin Lawlor, No. 5381, Sep 1908 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - United States District Court, District of CT: Loewe v. Lawlor (transcript vol. 1), 1912 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - untitled printed volume (same material as Box 32 folder 2), undated (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - United States District Court, District of CT: Loewe v. Lawlor (transcript vol. 2), 1912 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - United States District Court, District of CT: Loewe v. Lawlor (transcript vol. 3), 1912 (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - United States District Court, District of CT: Loewe v. Lawlor (transcript vol. 4), 1912 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - United States District Court, District of CT: Loewe v. Lawlor (transcript vol. 5), 1912 (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - United States Circuit Court of Appeals, 2nd Circuit: Lawlor v. Loewe-Transcript of Record (vol. 1), undated (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - United States Circuit Court of Appeals, 2nd Circuit: Lawlor v. Loewe-Transcript of Record (vol. 2), undated (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - United States Circuit Court of Appeals, 2nd Circuit: Lawlor v. Loewe-Transcript of Record (vol. 3), undated (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - United States Circuit Court of Appeals, 2nd Circuit: Lawlor v. Loewe-Transcript of Record (vol. 4), undated (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - United States Circuit Court of Appeals, 2nd Circuit: Lawlor v. Loewe-Transcript of Record (vol. 5), undated (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - United States Circuit Court of Appeals, 2nd Circuit: Lawlor v. Loewe, Classified Index, undated (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - United States Circuit Court of Appeals, 2nd Circuit: Lawlor v. Loewe, Brief for Plaintiff in Error, undated (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - United States Circuit Court of Appeals, 2nd Circuit: Lawlor v. Loewe, Brief for Plaintiff in Error, undated (Box 36, Folder 5)